A Guide to the Margaret Freeman Cabell Papers 1910-1982
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Series XI--Publications and Miscellaneous Printed Matter
  - A Testimonial, newspaper article 1938 (Box 53)
  - Goudy, Mary P. Emmett, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Father Frederic, n.d. (Box 53)
  - The Type Speaks I am the voice of Today-The Herald of Tomorrow, n.d. (Box 53)
  - F.W.G. Excerpt from NBC Broadcast 1934 (Box 53)
  - Frederick W. Goudy Dead at 82, New York Herald12 May 1947 (Box 53)
  - Here's to You Fred, by Wilbur Macey Stone 1938 (Box 53)
  - Selling a Type Face to Fred Goudy, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Thanksgiving at Deepdene: A letter to her Sister Elsea, by Berth M. Goudy 1925 (Box 53)
  - Alac! Poor Frederic, by Earl H. Emmons 1938 (Box 53)
  - Selected from Prose Francies by Richard Le Gallienne 1930s (Box 53)
  - Goudy by Branch Cabell 1903-1938 (Box 53)
  - Letter from Fred W. Goudy to J.B. Cabell 1938 (Box 53)
  - Goudy Number, Monotype, A Journal of Composing Room Efficiency 1928 (Box 53)
  - FWG: An Appreciation by R. Hunter Middleton 1938 (Box 53)
  - Son of Goudy: An Open Letter to Frederic W. Goudy from his Nearest Kin and Severest Critic 1938 (Box 53)
  - Intimate Recollections of the Village Press, by Three Friends 1938 (Box 53)
  - Types of the Past-Type Revivals with a few Words on Type Design in General 1936 (Box 53)
  - Commemorating the Presentation of a Medal of Honor to Frederic W. Goudy by the Ulster-Irish Society of New York for Notable Service to the Nation 1937 (Box 53)
- Series XII--Oversize Materials in the Scrapbook Area
  These items have their own numbering system
  - Edmund Waller, Will 1687 (Box 1)
  - William A. Patterson, Marriage License 1865 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore Life Insurance Company's The American Scene (Box 1)
  - Les Philantropes Du Jour, French Illustrations (Box 1)
  - 18th century English Drawing To the Benevoloent Ladies of Great Britain, who so liberally supported the new system of military cloathing this print is dedicated 1793 (Box 1)
  - The Reviewer, Old Dominion Trust Co., Kledger 1921 (Box 1)
  - Index to Publishers, Ballantine Books, Inc. 1960s-1970s (Box 1)
  - Ledger/Check Book 1958 (Box 1)
  - Unused Postcard from the Washington Cathedral Collection (Box 1)
  - The Record of F.W. Goudy Types 1938 (Box 2)
  - Ancient Customs Used in a Printing House 1938 (Box 2)
  - Evening a Deepdene, by F.W. Goudy (Box 2)
  - Drawing by Fred Copper, commemorating the 35th anniversary of the Village Press 1938 (Box 2)
  - Sketch of J.M. Freeman by Deborah (Box 3)
  - Uncle Bruce and Irma Cartoon 1979 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Trial Sketchbook 1980 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 3)
  - Drawing of J.M. Freeman by Casey Lynn Sims, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Sketch of an Unknown Woman (Box 3)
  - Sketch of a Richmond Teenager (Box 3)
  - Robyn, n.d. (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook, n.d. (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Photograph of St. Patrick's Cathedral (Box 3)
  - Letter from Ballard Cabell to John M. Freeman 1961 (Box 3)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook with Portrait of Margaret Cabell (Box 3)
  - Rocky and Vicki Sketch (Box 3)
  - John as a Name Poem (Box 3)
  - Verses from the Mapmaker of Mott (Box 3)
  - Drawing of a Girl with Glasses (Box 3)
  - Jackie of Buckingham Co. 1980 (Box 3)
  - Unvelievable Gerry at the Whit Tower 1980 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by J.M. Freeman (Box 3)
  - Water Color Sketches by John Middleton Freeman, n.d. (Map-case 26.1)
  - Pen and Marker Drawings by John Middleton Freeman 1970s (Map-case 26.2)
  - Sketches of a Nude Female, n.d. (Map-case 26.3)
  - Notebook, Ellwood Art Poster by John Middleton Freeman 1980 (Map-case 26.4)